they could try to um instead inject
What's called the closed Shadow D
okay the Shadow do yeah did they do that
from they did that from the isolated
world right yeah they did
[Music]
[Applause]
sup y'all if you've listened to critical
thinking for any time at all you know
that we very often cover the asset note
teams research that they put out on
Enterprise security and zero days that
they've been popping left and right um
and lucky for us now the team had no
longer just has a Blog but they've got a
podcast called surfacing security where
they talk about everything Enterprise
security related um and a tax surface
management related and I've I've been
following each episode and just just
listen to these episode titles Okay
Internet wide Recon moving past IP
Centric approaches very interesting
Beyond Shadow it understanding the true
attack surface of your software this
one's focused on like thirdparty
softwares and how they can affect your
Enterprise security um posture and the
unknown complexities of DNS resolution
Guys these guys know DNS resolution like
no one I've ever met I've probably spent
10 plus hours just to discussing DNS
resolution and their DNS Pipeline with
the Asino team and they know their [__]
inside outside upside down um so if any
of those sound interesting to you check
out the new surfacing security podcast
on the asset note YouTube channel or
wherever you get your podcast all right
back to the
show all righty dude we're rolling Matan
welcome back man good to be back very
excited for this one we have a banger
episode coming up we really do man and
we have uh not a lot of things on the
docket which means we can go deep into
them only only three topics one of which
is browser extensions which I feel
somehow we got to six pages we did get
to six fages so so we'll see we'll see
if uh we'll see if we get through all of
it uh but I think Bowser extensions are
kind of a really underserved attack
surface in bug Bounty and I think that
because you told me
that yeah I've been kind of capitalizing
on it but I think I'm going to have more
competition after this episode you know
yeah dude thanks for thanks for agreeing
to do it because I know um when we were
talking about preing for this episode
you were like maybe we'll push this
episode out a little bit maybe I should
I should milk this a little bit more I
thought I stopped milking it but then in
preparation for this episode I took
another look at some of the extensions I
tried to act and I still found some bugs
in there so yeah definitely stuff to
find okay so I'm going to say that this
one is a a browser extension hacking
version one because I know there are
some things that you've discovered
recently that you haven't fully had the
time to and we're not gonna we're not
going to drop them completely yet um but
maybe we can get those someday that
would be that would be
cool yeah um all right let's let's uh
let's get into it man um browser
extensions I guess the first thing that
we need to understand is what is the
structure of these browser extensions
and what is the the threat model before
we get into that I just want to say that
this episode might be a little hard to
follow especially in audio form you know
um just because it's it's going to be
unfamiliar to a lot of people and the
structure of a browser extension can be
a little complicated you really have to
visualize it which might be a little
tough so don't worry if you don't get it
the first time um I think you can just
learn from experience you know messing
with an extension is going to teach you
a lot about how extensions are built way
more than I can sort of explain via
audio but anyways the way extensions are
built and first of all just in general
we all know what extensions are but
their purpose can be either to extend
the functionality of a set of sites can
be one site multiple sites or all Sites
or of the browser itself right you can
maybe change the theme of the browser or
something like that and in order to do
that if you sort of think about it a lot
of the time extensions um need to have
sort of a way to run code in the site
that they want to extend right and on
top of that they need some sort of um
thing that coordinates all of this you
know because you can have like many many
tabs of the same site say you're trying
to extend youtube.com and you have like
multiple scripts it can get kind of
messy you need something to coordinate
all of it and so the browser developers
sort of build like an extension
component for each one of these roles so
in order to execute um code in the sites
that you're trying to extend say it's
like all Sites um one example that I had
for like a simple extension that we can
sort of keep in mind um while we're
talking about it is an an extension that
I will call like save my jpegs okay and
it's just going to add a save button to
every image on the page so every image
element in every page is it's just going
to add a save button that will save it
to some site so um in order to do that
we will need to inject some J code into
every site that's open in the victim's
in the victim's
browser you're already thinking about it
from from the attacker perspective I
that's it's funny you say that CU that's
literally how I talk all the time with
yeah I'm auto correcting constantly
um so we we're going to need to inject
code into every um page in the potential
victims browser um now the sort of
component that does that in browser
extensions it's called the content
script so you can have many content
scripts in the browser extension and
they can be injected in a few different
ways it's kind of it gets a little
complicated um but basically what you'll
see in like most
cases um is the sort of config file of
the
extension uh um which is like a Json
file um it will just have like the
content scripts that you will that will
be injected and a list of like which
sites it will inject to and actually um
before we continue um it's important to
note that the sort of structure and
behavior is a bit different between the
um last version of extensions called
manifest V3 might have heard of it
because there was some noise about it
yeah and um manifest V2 right and
because um Chrome is going in in the
direction of manifest V3 and all of the
big companies have already
updated and I chose to focus just on
manifest V3 so that's what we're going
to talk about um so anyways when we want
to make like the save my jpegs extension
we're going to have all of the content
scripts each injected into a different
tab or if frame or whatever like every
page that renders we're going to have a
Content script in it now
um we need like something to coordinate
all of it so sort of the brains of the
extension the like main script that runs
and coordinates everything that has like
the capability to inject content scripts
and stuff like that um it used to be
called the background script now it's
called the service worker
which is very like that that
changed that makes that makes sense now
cuz I I was like I heard both of those
terminologies and I was like I don't see
where this fits into the structure but
they're actually just the same thing so
it's very confusing calling it the
service worker yeah and it actually has
some differences between it and like a
regular service worker so I'm not sure
what why they pick that ter and anyways
it's called the service worker and it
sort of runs in the background and
coordinates everything
right so there's a little graphic here
that you have um and I'll show it yeah
it's taken from um space raccoon's blog
actually with about browser extension
haing and which was pretty great you can
read it after the
episode um but the actually the little
diagram isn't um totally
complete uh
because um you can see if you're looking
at a at the pod on YouTube and there's
sort of like a section about the web
page Dom which is sort of the site that
is getting extended basically and it has
like a Content script in this case a few
content scripts that were injected by
the extension and it has like the
original JS code that's running inside
the site and what space raccoon chose to
highlight here is that those two can
communicate via post message and
got the space recruit plushy right here
man ready to go let's
go those two scripts can communicate via
post message but they can also
communicate via other channels and like
custom events stuff like that we're
going to get into it a bit further um
then that um content script can
communicate with the background script
the service
worker um via a browser API called the
message passing
API there there's a bunch of functions
that are pretty similar to post message
and that's just how they communicate um
so that's the basic structure you can
add some some stuff on top of that um
like some ex some extensions will have
like another script that runs inside the
um the actual context of the web page um
but we're going to get into that a
little bit further yeah so so let me let
me let me try to summarize this really
quick because there there is a pretty
complex structure here okay we have
three main compon or two really two main
components that you've mentioned so far
well if we can count manifest.json it'll
be three right so we've got the the
content script right which is the script
that the extension injects into the Dom
of the actual page that the user is on
so depending on the configuration file
this could be you know any any website
it could be a certain set of websites
maybe like star. cb. show or whatever or
it it could be just one you know
specific website that it wants to modify
that's the content script and that is
affecting that is sharing the Dom with
the actual JS not sharing the content
the actual JS environment right well I'm
gonna I'm was just gonna talk about it
so okay all right all right hit it hit
it hit it yeah so basically if you sort
of take the structure that we explained
so far injecting a content script
straight into the page and implement it
there's a bit of a problem that comes up
that the sort of chrome developers or
browser developers in general had to
solve so imagine you have like a site
and say it's malicious you know and you
inject that content script straight into
the um JS environment of that site right
now you have you want to give the
content script a certain level of
privilege right right it has to have the
ability to say communicate with a
background script or read cookies from
Pages stuff like that whatever
permissions the extension has but you
don't want the regular environment of
the site that you're injecting into
which can be malicious and to have that
same level of privilege so you need to
have some way of separating the two and
once you do that you also have to make
sure that the sort of environments can't
mess with each other m mainly that the
um that the malitia site can't mess with
the content script and because then it
could manipulate it in and somehow take
advantage of the Privileges it has and
if you if you share that JS environment
at all you're just kind of opening up a
can of worms right like like you you
because there's so much so many things
you have to think of from like prototype
pollution and uh various variable
hijacking or whatever so they need to do
something different yeah anyone who's
tried to create a JavaScript sandbox
yeah like the one that was used to be in
Angular JS before they G up gave up yeah
knows that it's a tough tough problem to
solve right um yeah there's a whole
bunch of stuff that can go wrong there
so what the Chrome developer
specifically chose to do I think it
works a little bit differently on
Firefox but I haven't looked at that um
is they chose to make the code of the
content script run in what's called an
isol at world so such a cool name no
such a cool name it it's a bad name like
I I breached the isolated world oh my
gosh dude that's like top tier hacker
[__] right there if you breach the
isolated world
yeah so uh what the isolated World sort
of does is it makes the um the contentp
still kind of runs in the page because
the extension has to have the ability to
like modify the D read the location
stuff like that it has to sort of feel
like it's in the page um but it sort of
um prevents the um the page from messing
with the extension in the sense that if
the page like sets a global global
variable say it overwrites window. alert
to be some [__]
function now um that will like reflect
in the um actual context of the page
that over over it but if you look at the
isolated World window. alert will remain
the same so you can't really influence
that there is a bit of a catch there but
I'm still milking it oh
my I know what you're talking about
about it's it's a good one I'm excited
to release that in in in a little while
in a while in a while in a while no no
rush I'm not rushing you I'm just saying
yeah it'll be a good one when I retire
yeah sure sure at 19
anyways yeah in in two years yeah in a
few years yeah anyways um the isolated
World um is sort of there to prevent the
as we talked about a malicious page from
messing with the content script but in
some
cases um extensions will want or have
to uh run JS in the actual context of
the page in the actual world of the page
say you want to make like a competitor
extension to France rosen's and post
message tracker okay right right you
need to override the sort of Ed event
listener or um I don't know um window.on
message Setter stuff like that sure so
that when a new post message listener
gets added you need to catch that
um so in order to override it if you try
to override it in the content in the
isolated World it won't affect the
actual page so you need to actually
inject JS into the actual page and then
override that sort of actual like ad
event listener yeah I think this gets
tricky a little bit too I was talking to
Kevin Mizu the author of um dum logger
Plus+ about this is you know with that
structure that that the Chrome
developers have put in into place um you
know you're you're having to either you
know append a script to the page or use
I think one other route that the there
is to to inject a script and that that
has uh a delay to it right it's not
instantaneous um and and so there are
some events that won't get caught by Dom
logger Plus+ for like the first like 20
milliseconds or whatever it is until it
it runs its its um you know overwrite
script because of that delay the issue
that don't blogger Plus+ is trying to
solve is hard to solve with an
extension um it's like a lot simpler
than forking Chrome but it's hard to
solve with an extension and yeah yeah
forking Chrome that's you're opening up
a can of worms a little bit there if you
do that I mean it it it would be really
cool and I would love to see somebody
approach the the problem right where
where you Fork Chrome and somehow you
keep it up to date in consistent with
chrome and you have a a you know a good
amount of like updates and that sort of
thing but take out some of these these
um you know things that hinder us to
have introspection further into security
um yeah but it would be much easier if
the Chrome devs just did this so if
anybody at Google is listening and you
have a an in at the at the Chrome team
let me know because it would be really
nice if we could just get a couple Flags
put into place that would allow us to
overwrite things like document document
location um or window location hre and
like get get introspection into those
specific attributes there's that and
also um if a reason to for Chrome is um
right now you can't sort of have a Dom
logger equivalent for testing browser
extensions because Dom logger as a
browser extension doesn't have the
Privileges to mess with the JS of other
extensions um so that would also be a
reason yeah yeah okay all right so we
can get back to the structure but let me
let me review for a second because we've
covered a lot of ground okay so so we've
got the manifest.json file that's the
configuration file for the extension
right right and that defines a bunch of
different things uh two of them are uh
the uh content scripts which get
injected into the Dom of the page but
not in the same JS environment they're
in an isolated world right so if they
want not exactly into the Dom but like
into into the page and but in a separate
World they they they get injected into
the to the the page in a separate JS
world and have access to the Dom is that
accurate yeah okay all right just glad
we got got that squared away there okay
so they're in for being a little
scuttled here no no no no no I I I need
this is exactly what we need to
understand it thoroughly and we can't
hack it if we don't understand it
thoroughly so this is great and and
actually the plus of that is that um the
content script can affect the the Dom
and and affect the JS execution in the
normal uh execution world the
non-isolated
world um by injecting a script into the
into the Dom which would trigger the
there are a few ways to do that so
basically we're right now we're talking
about sort of a separate component of
the um of what H an extension could look
like so we have like the two very
standard components the content script
and the um backgound script or service
worker whatever you want to call it um
but some extensions will need to have a
separate component we can call it like
the injected script yeah um that's just
how I was I saw it referred to in one of
the extensions I've looked at um so the
injected
script um it has to be like a script
that runs in the actual world of um the
page that is getting
extended right so
um for the extensions that do need that
functionality which is not too many
extensions but it's pretty common um a
few ways to do that would be either to
add an actual script element to Theon
and which is what I think down logger
does and um post message tracker does or
um there are a bunch of native ways to
do that in the
um in
the uh actual ch um the CH apis so
um
the you have uh either you can set like
you can add another content script and
set a special flag there to make sure
that that script is injected into the
actual world of the um of the page or
you could use some other function I
forgot what's what's it called anyways
there are a few ways to do it's provid a
certain option execution world is that
it when injecting the content
script uh yeah yeah execution World the
Main I think nice nice okay so you can
Define the the the world the the the uh
the the world that this thing is
executing in I like that that's good I
don't know what it is about the world
the world but it just sounds so like
anime right like like it's like in this
world we'll be executing anyway okay
okay so we've got that those
World from all the exactly exactly so
we've got the we've got the content
script it it's the thing that's
injecting into the page we can Define
scripts for the actual JS um execution
world that's normal right so that that's
where a lot of the functionality is
happening but then also in the Manifest
Json file we also have the service
worker also known as the background
script that that um is not a part of
doesn't have access to the Dom and uh is
just sort of like a backend process for
the extension that can communicate with
the content script yeah I'm not sure
that it doesn't have because I think
there are a lot of weird ways to do
stuff like directly from the background
script but usually what you'll see is
like it will communicate with the
content script and the content script
handles all of these tasks so we should
probably think of the background script
as like or or the or the service worker
as the as like the backend code of sorts
for for the extension versus the front
end code which is the content script
it's actually where you're supposed to
implement the most sensitive
functionality because it's the part that
is least exposed to um to the actual
like to a malicious attacker in the
actual Chrome docs they mentioned that
you shouldn't trust any communication
between the background script and the
content script because they assume the
content script is um compromised really
even in isolated world even
world yeah it's theoretically I can
understand where they come from but you
can't actually Implement that if you
have a complicated extension you're
always going to have some sensitive
stuff in the content script yeah yeah
and I think I think in space raccoons
space raccoons uh write up you know he
sort of mentions a scenario where uh
essentially they're they're just they're
using post message to communicate from
the the JS environment on the on the
page the normal JS environment to the
content script and that content script
is then passing that message straight
through pretty much to the background
script via the send message Api right um
and in that scenario it's like okay well
sure if you if you code up the content
script in such a way that you're just
arbitrarily passing Json messages
through you're sort of breaking a
boundary then you do sort of violate
that trust boundary I I can see that so
anyways I was going to talk about
something a little similar to that we
mentioned the injected script component
that an extension can have again it's
like not mandatory it's optional um so
the interesting thing is if you look at
the communication between that um that
little component and the content script
because it can't um access the
background script directly if you look
at that communication and think about it
a little whatever that communication is
however they implemented it it can be
hijacked and that's because the injected
script it's in the actual environment of
the attacker and attacker has like full
control over it and however you're going
to try to interact with that content
script whether it's via with that sorry
injected script whether it's via post
message or custom events or something
like that an attacker can imitate that
like very easily and you can't do Like
An Origin check because they're going to
have the same oen yeah yeah cuz it's the
same JS execution environment even yeah
yeah wow okay so so we've got that that
attack surface as well you've got the
attack surface of any scripts injected
by the content script you've got the
content script attacking the content
script itself um and then I guess trying
to attack the backend script via proxy
of sorts through the content script as
far as attack vectors go for these
extensions do you want to start getting
into attack vectors yeah I mean well
okay let me just let me just try to
repeat back to you and you can validate
my understanding of the structure Okay
so we've got the Manifest Jon I I know
we've already done this a couple times I
know but it's very hard that's why I had
the disclaimer at the start yeah it gets
it gets complicated actually I'm going
to go ahead and just share the share the
screen again for those of you that are
on YouTube um so you can see the the um
the graph and and then hopefully this
will make a little bit more sense okay
so okay so first we've got the Manifest
Json file which is not actually
displayed in that graph so let me scroll
up here's here's something that that
kind of looks like the Manifest Json
file right you're defining these content
scripts you define where they are you
descri describe a Rex of sort it's not
really a Rex but it's like a pattern on
what pages this these content scripts
should be injected um and then now we've
injected the content script the content
script is in the web page but in an
isolated world right so it doesn't share
a JS execution environment with the
original js on that web page and the
content script is able to inject scripts
into the page and and affect the um JS
execution environment um of the the of
the web page but the original JS does
not have the ability to do the opposite
of that right and like affect the the
content script because of the isolated
the
isolated um and then and then the
primary ways for these things to
communicate is via post message so the
original JS can send a post message to
the content script and vice versa and
then we also have this other component
which we consider sort of like the back
end of the um of the extension which is
the back script or the service worker
and the content script can communicate
with the background script via the send
message Api so that's sort of it's kind
of like post message but for that
backend to front end communication for
the extensions however the front-end JS
the original JS cannot communicate to
the back background script directly
using the send message Api so if you're
trying to attack the the the background
script you kind of have to do that via
proxy through the the the content script
exactly get all that right yeah all
right can can I get a round of applause
for that please just from you thank you
thank you all right very good hey guys
our sponsor project Discovery has
dropped a new tool in collaboration with
Google's own Mandan team called TLD
finder okay picture the SubFinder but
for top level domains need I say anymore
check it out and I and I suppose I
should probably give you a Round of
Applause well for actually like
explaining the the the thing so to try
to no it's great man all right so so now
let's talk about what how we can attack
these Chrome extensions now that we sort
of understand what they are stru okay
yeah okay so I want to like do a few
distinctions here um between like
different attack scenarios and attack
surfaces um so I think the best attack
scenario or like attack
surface is um the the case where you
have like uh the extension trying to
extend the malicious page so if it's
like um I save my jpex extension um it
it will try to extend every page add
like buttons to it um so when the victim
navigates to a Malicia page that that's
where you have that sort of attack
scenario um and is this is this the
extension extending the page with a
Content script or is it it's injecting
the script into it the are we talking
about the injected script are we talking
about the just a Content script just a
cont cont scpt okay okay sure and the
injector script is sort of like a subase
of that sure sure so when you have that
content script in there um even though
they have like an isolated World it
Stills opens it still opens a whole
bunch of attack surface that isn't very
standard and you might not think about
um for example because they share the D
the two walls they have like the bridge
of the D it's getting even more even
more dramatic um if the uh extension
injects something into the into the Dom
like in our EX in our example uh button
then from the attacker JS code in that
page you could just like do button do
click right right because it's a part of
that Dom they're sharing the D right or
like if it injects a paragraph you could
just read the content of the paragraph
uh so so so let's say the the extension
makes a button on the page and then the
extension itself registers an event
handler um to that button event like a
click or something like that then so
okay sorry I had to sneeze there for a
second but but you're so then you they
you can actually simulate that by
actually just on the JS side clicking
that button which is the equivalent of
executing the function in the content
script because of the event handler is
that accurate yeah there's a little
caveat there because why wouldn't there
be events have have like a weird
um property like the actual um event
object that gets like sent when to the
event listener when an event happens
they have the is trusted
property and for click events is trusted
is only uh said to true if the click was
actually
done by the user interesting so that's
that's a sort of a defense in depth
technique that they could use is check
whether it's a trusted click or not but
what you can do as an attacker if you
have just like the button there you can
mess with its style make it full screen
stuff like that get creative basically
sure but it prevents you from just going
click click click click click and um
that that makes sense but I I think also
man one of the crazy things to me about
situations like this where where you
have control of CSS
is how much we have programmed users to
just click accept cookies or Define
cookies whatever you click right like
like when you come to a page do you even
think about it anymore like
do do okay well you know maybe I'm I'm
I'm I'm the the Sheep here whatever but
like you know you're going to harvest a
click one way or the other right with
that every single time and then like
maybe you make the button de press you
know go down and then come back up and
then it doesn't go away going to do
you're going to click it again you know
and so I think we we' programmed users
to mindlessly click on something as soon
as they go to the page which you know
maybe it's a win for privacy because you
have an opt-in or an opt out for for
cookies but uh it's definitely an L
for action required bugs it's it's not
it's not really an L because um you
could always just make a victim click
somewhere on your side it's like not
it's not supposed to be a it so
frictionless though like maybe it's not
I don't know maybe that's my my hot take
but I I just think it's like I it's
almost like opening it like I click a
link and I don't even see that box and I
still click it you know yeah so yeah
anyways um I'm sorry go ahead so when we
talk about the the case of browser
extension specifically the content
script injecting UI into a malicious
page there are a bunch of ways to do
that right um so we just talked about
injecting the elements directly but if
they are sort of aware of this attack
scenario they could sort of go around
that a little bit um so they could try
to um instead inject What's called the
closed Shadow D okay
oh the shadow Dum yeah did they do that
from they did that from the isolated
world right yeah they did is
world I'm sorry I'm tripping today I'm
tripping okay so they're going to
they're going to put it in a closed
Shadow do closed Shadow D um
luckily
maswa the goat did some research on
closed Shadow dos and I should explain
what that is um a shadow do is sort of
like another document inside the
document so the same way you have like
an iframe which is another document
inside the document and but um it's
interesting thing because it sort of
isolates um what JavaScript can access a
certain element um so say you have like
JavaScript running in function a and
JavaScript running in function B um
function a can like create an element
add a closed Shadow D to it and then
append that element like add some some
content to that closed Shadow D and then
when it
that element to the Dom attaches it
function B can't access the content of
the clo Shadow Dom can can function a
though because I was under the
impression that once oh really okay
that's interesting I was under the
impression that once the shadow Dom hit
the the the the Dom that it was sort of
Untouchable it's like the I think the
way it works and I haven't done a lot of
testing with it but I think the way it
works is um the sort of f you have like
a reference to the variable when you
created that okay and kind of like
when right right um it's interesting
that you mention me Message Board
because
um maybe there are some tricks where you
can like override a bunch of prototypes
to try to get a handle to that original
um Shadow Dom variable anyways very
interesting in this case we can do it
because yeah that's great okay so
they're putting it in in a shadow Dom
yeah theoretically if they put it in a
shadow Dom then um you can't like mess
with any Styles or maybe I think you can
actually so you can mess with Styles and
and you can like click Jack it you know
because you can overlay some UI on top
of it and now what masato did is some
research and you actually covered it on
the Pod yeah dude I freaking love it
it's amazing with font liur yeah so you
can use that research to leak content
from that closed Shadow Dom um so we
have like three level three separate
levels of vulnerability here one is if
they inject an element straight into the
page then you can do whatever you want
with it um the second case is when they
inject a closed Shadow d
um or a shadow rout then you can leak
stuff from it but it's sort of using a
technique that I don't know how intended
it is um you can lick stuff from it and
you can click check it and I think mess
with sty and now the fourth level is if
they inject it in an i frame okay so
they have an i frame um either to the
extensions origin which looks like
Chrome Das extension
sl/ the extensions ID and then some um
HTML page or to just some site of the uh
Chrome extension developer um so if they
inject that into the page then you can't
mess with any Styles or something
because it's in an ey frame but you can
still click check it so whatever way you
go there's no really running away from
the problem that UI that gets injected
into a malicious page will always be
clickable and and that has impact in
these scenarios because it is tied
directly to the functionality that is
defined in the content script right so
you know clickjacking a button that that
you know may not have any Direct
Security impact isn't going to get you a
bounty likely on these on these scripts
but if if you can yeah don't just goting
it right yeah I always just feel like I
have to disclose that scenario like
clickjacking gets a bad rap because
people
don't exploit it correctly but if you
like I think you mentioned somewhere in
in the dock here Matan but like like
metamask had like a 120k bug right that
was that was pretty much clickjacking
right yeah yeah so it's like you we got
to we got to you got to outline the full
threat model and then clickjacking can
be a really really serious bug
especially in this extension environment
right right right and um we're actually
going to talk about the metamask buug a
little more um the tech details are very
interesting there's like a little caveat
there that the metamask developers
missed it's fun let me let me repeat
this back to you real quick okay so
we've got three levels of of U sort of
attack ability here you've got um if the
content script injects some UI into the
attacker control Dom uh directly then we
can click it we can modify it we can do
whatever and then um when the thing
actually gets clicked then it will
trigger something in the content script
yeah um and we can there is some some
caveat to that with the trusted sort of
thing right whether the event is trusted
or not but um we got some work arounds
with that with clickjacking and if we
use the shadow
Dom then then you can you can um it's
sort of like read but no right right
right like you can leak the contents of
what is injected into the shadow Dom but
then but you can't actually like
uh you you can't actually um you know
click it or trigger any events because
it's isolated away
um and then the third the third layer is
just using an ey frame right which is
just you know I feel like you've got
that Meme with like the frame the Galaxy
brain you know that that it's just like
let's just use an iframe guys um and and
that one is it doesn't allow you to do
uh like CSS styling or or anything like
that but you can still of course click
Jack it Vana clickjacking basically yeah
and and you mentioned that there are
like these pages that um you can load up
in UI these this is another component of
of the um of the extension and that's
those are extension pages right um oh
yeah I forgot to mention it's so um no
no you're good so so extension pages are
like the the third component of of the
whole um uh extension that that we
created we've got the we've got the the
background script which is the service
worker you've got the the content script
which gets injected into the page uh but
is in an isolated world and then you got
this third component which is the um
extension pages and those can be HTML or
just pretty much any attribute like any
like file that's attached to the
extension so an extension is just like a
fancy bundle of files it's a yeah a zip
with a signature and has just a bunch of
files um so those files can be HTML
files right and there are a few uses for
it for example when you click on an
extension icon there's a little popup
that goes up there right that's just one
of the HTML files that's in the
extension source and or if you like
right click it and go to the ex options
page and that's another HTML file so
those are like two standard um pages but
um an extension page is just like an
HTML file in that origin um and because
it's in the that like an ex the
extension can open normally can put it
in an if frame or something like that
there are bit of caveat there but we'll
get to it
um for shadowing this episode
yeah um okay yeah so those uh Pages
because they're in the um extensions
origin they have like special privileges
they can connect to the um hive mind the
background script and um or sorry the
service worker and um communicate with
it because they're in the um extensions
origin um and there's some very
interesting attack surface there okay so
now that we're done covering the UI
stuff mhm um which to be clear is the
case where malicious UI is injected into
um an attacker controlled Page by a
Content script or whatever okay so we
we're covering content script attack
vors right now and the the segment of
that was injecting into an attack
controlled page yeah so those UI
a second attack scenario is um any
communication between that page or like
an injected script and the content
script and so that can be custom uh
event listeners um which we look like ad
event listener and then some name that
you don't recognize or some name that
you do recognize you can still exploit
those um so just like event listeners in
general um that the sort of content
script ads and and so in in this
scenario like typically with with post
message exploitation if we're going to
if they're going to add like an event
listener for that we need a window
reference so how do we get a window
reference to these oh it's the same
window so we just send it to
ourselves um yeah so one the um ex post
messages specifically are interesting
because you can either um have the
attack scenario where it's injected into
the page and then you can send it to
yourself or um you can have this
scenario where it's injected into a um a
sort of a legitimate page and in that
case you have like um you can send a
malicious message um so you have a bit
less control over the input right
because that message will have like a
malicious origin so they can verify that
and like um block you when you say
legitimate page this would be like this
would be like more more like the
traditional um uh post message attack
Vector structure right so you've got
like two tabs open one is the attacker
page one is the victim page with the
extension loaded up in the content
script injected into it and you're
sending a message from the attacker page
to the legitimate page or or the victim
page in this scenario and getting a bit
ahead of
myself is is that accurate though right
is that accurate accurate okay I'm
getting a bit ahead of myself because I
was going to talk about it in a second
okay
so this the second attack scenario of um
injecting into a malicious page is as we
mentioned post message listeners or
event uh listeners in general because if
the um if the uh content script listens
for whatever event on document.body you
can do document.body do dispatch event
and some event that you created right
yeah we have more flexibility there yeah
mhm you just have some functions that
you can reach um and you can imag if
it's like I don't know a click event
or another event that then the content
script does something does something
with like send a message as a result of
that to the background script that does
something you can just sort of hijack
that logic basically you can trigger
that action with an event listener um
and I've seen in some cases even like
taking some input from the event so you
have um like the event. detail uh
property and which is attacker
controllable and taking some input from
that and doing stuff is that like is
that like like a data property or is
from from post message or does details
contain something else um it's it's very
similar um when you have like a custom
event you can initiate it with um
something in its
detail um so uh you can have like a a
string in the the details an object
something like that data passed when
initializing the event I see okay
interesting um so I've seen and in that
case I actually had to manipulate the
extension a bit to get it to listen to
those events um but I managed to set up
some scenario where it listened to those
events and then um I could do some
interesting stuff because I trigger that
event then the content script past that
detail to the background scpt and it did
something with it okay so we are we are
we're pivoting even here from from the
the your frontend scenario I I guess and
then pivoting through the content script
over to the background script with this
C EV that's the closest I'm going to get
to hacking back yeah exactly well I mean
that's all you can do right um yeah and
and I guess what is what is the goal in
these scenarios like are we trying to
get the the content script to like it's
very hard to Define yeah like are we
trying to get can we pop xss in the
extension Pages or are we trying to like
get malicious cont that's a great
question I forgot to mention that too um
so in every scenario every attack
scenario you can never get JS execution
in the actual origin of the extension
right so you can't actually get it to
execute some js and then use all the
apis that it has and because in manifest
V3 there's a mandatory CSP that they
have to implement that doesn't allow any
scripts other than the scripts that came
bundled with the
extension okay so no no eval no no no
eval nothing yeah um okay in that yeah
that's bad that's bad yeah um I'm sorry
I got a bit too late into extension iing
a bit too late and I missed that but
it's fine yeah dude
there's still plenty of stuff to exploit
to hijack the whole the whole content
script and have that back yeah um so you
can't do that but um it's very possible
to say the extension um adds um or I
don't know somehow does something
insecure you can maybe theoretically get
it to execute attacker control scripts
in
um legitimate pages right because
there's nothing in the inherent
structure that prevents that from
happening in the actual in the pages uh
of the website okay I see so legitimate
page is the the page of the victim
website that you would be attacking
right okay yeah and so like it's let's
say they're listening for a post message
they're not doing An Origin check and
then they're concatenating a script to
the Dom or whatever with that with that
data then that would be a scenario where
we're attacking the legitimate page via
the content script right um so that's
that's um kind of not really what we're
um oh I guess it is possible to um in
every one of the attack scenarios that
we're going to mention I think it's
theoretically possible to get that to
happen somehow um and you can like in
the best case scenario or worst case
scenario however you want to look at it
you can get Universal xss out of that
yeah yeah which is very bad that's very
bad that is not good if I have like an
extension that millions of people
installed and like people can just read
their emails and yeah that's bad that is
that is very bad indeed okay so so the
the Holy Grail in this sort of scenario
for extension hacking is sort of this
Universal xss scenario yeah yeah so we
we're done covering the what happens
when a Content script is injected into a
malicious page now let's talk about what
happens when it's injected into a normal
page a legitimate page okay and so that
case is very interesting because you
have like a bit less input as the
attacker um but you have many more syns
or like much more potential for stuff to
go wrong if you get input somewhere um
because the content script is injected
into a normal page and the content
script has like access to all of the D
apis like we mentioned so if it does
like document WR or something you can
just accss the legitimate page
right which if that page is every page
then a universal xss like we just
mentioned yeah um
so when you have a legitimate page the
things to look out for is one are there
any post message listeners if not can
you get it to add a post message
listener um in some specific scenario
that's a great point right like like
often times what we'll do is we'll look
at you know we'll load up a page and
we'll look at whether the the post
message listeners are there I way too
much yeah but but I think there's a lot
of scenarios where you need to click a
button on that page for that listener to
be registered and then something happens
and that's where I've been seeing a lot
of post message
lately yeah so you can have that all
sort of the attack surface here in the
case of a cond script injected into a
regular page is very similar to just the
normal attack surface that you would
have when you try to act the legitimate
page directly because the content script
can like have I don't know take URL
parameters stuff like that because it
has access to the location so it's
pretty much the same um you can have
like you have the same sort of what I
call um Universal input sources um which
is like location data and post message
data stuff like that
okay gotta you could of course have like
Target specific input
sources um depending on the
functionality of the extension but um in
general that scenario is very similar to
um
the the scenario of just trying to hack
a page directly yeah and you imag noral
hacking yeah okay got you can imagine
that if an extension is very big
suddenly that adds a ton of attack
surface to every page the victim has
like every page in existence basically
that the victim can open which is a
little scary yeah um so if you have a
lot of extensions uh installed that's
something to worry about it's it's risky
man a lot of stuff is getting injected
into every single page it it's kind of I
I guess it makes a lot of sense that
they needed to do this isolated World
thing too because there's just going to
be so much Collision across extensions
and stuff like that as well if they were
showing the same that's also a reason
they do that yeah yeah yeah um Okay so
that makes sense on the legitimate when
it's getting injected into the
legitimate page we're just mostly
looking at the same sources in syns and
just considering these content scripts
as like a JS file included on the page
right yeah you can you can totally
abstract that way um yeah yeah so so
this is this is a question that I had
then so the legitimate page one is you
know less exciting like you said it's
more more exciting when you can get the
execution to actually trigger on an
attacker controlled page so then the
question then becomes how do we get the
ex the extension to trigger on attacker
controlled page and I know that that um
this is defined in the Manifest uh file
I'll I'll go ahead and share my screen
again so you guys can see what I'm
talking about from space raccoon's nice
article where there's a a graphic for
this but um you know I know that there's
a an environment where you can Define
essentially the matches array which
defines a pattern of sorts that uh this
extension will run on when it matches
the the the current path um the current
location um and I was looking at this
and I was like please God let it be a
Rex if it's if it's a Rex you know what
I'm thinking right mon on the dots the
dots would be amazing but it's not a Rex
uh it's an actual it's like a it's like
a custom syntax right that makes it a
little bit more difficult to to um get
it to execute in an environment where it
wasn't intended to execute um so have
you have you poked around on that at all
like is there there have you seen any
weird tricks that might result in an
attacker's page getting able to run the
the content scripts or interact with the
content scripts yeah when it comes to
that usually it's either like intended
and you'll see like all urls in the
matches pattern um like the literal
string all urls um okay that's like a
special case yeah that's a special case
with like brackets around it um or um
you will have like a page and a site
that they inject into and you can accss
that site and now it basically becomes
an attacker control site ah interesting
yeah and then the chain just gets way
too long you
know when then you're try to Pivot and
stuff like that if you because I know
that there's like wow oh oh interesting
interesting stuff because then you I
know that some of these extensions also
have a way for you to access cookie
storage that are ass
with other entities right so if there's
if there's a way that you can um that
you can get an xss on one of these
trusted domains and then interact with
the the extension do you know what I'm
talking about or do you not know what
I'm talking about yeah you mean like
getting an xss there then interacting
with the extension to somehow leak data
for other sites you can do that but
actually I want to say that there's
specifically yeah so scroll down to on
the on the space Recon article scroll
down to to um just go ahead and search
for permissions as a string right it
says in addition the extension has
permissions to access the cookies of
multiple other Origins and then it shows
like permissions cookies and then he he
describes in this scenario how the
application actually defines a an on
message listener that allows him to grab
cookies for any specific origin um and
and so let's say there was a similar
functionality with that you can take the
xss that you have in in a you know some
obscure subdomain whatever just like as
intended functionality having the
extension inject into a legitimate page
yeah yeah or an attack control page
sorry right right and and then the the
yeah wow that's that is some very
interesting interesting attack scenarios
then because this becomes a really
impactful way to
escalate uh xsss in obscure subdomains
if there if there's like a star do or
whatever in the in the matches for the
for the manifest.json and now that's
become an attacker controlled page via
the xss and you can interact with the
extension to do bad
things am I am I on on on track with
that yeah um so I'm looking at the um
like different conditions for whether to
inject a Content script or not um so
actually it's important to note that
currently we're talking just about the
Manifest file right
but that's not actually not the only way
you can inject content scripts um you
can have just the the code in the
service worker just go like um Chrome
tabs and just select a bunch of tabs and
add the content script to them manually
manually so you've got to read the the
whole um service worker code base as
well to make sure they're not dy I think
it's it's actually might be a bit of a
common pattern because you can just go
Chrome tabs query and then query for a
certain thing so say they have like
query for a certain URL or something
like that and then is that a query
selector no it's just a query I wish it
was a query selector Som chrome chrome
tabs query and then what are you passing
into it are you searching for URL some
object with a bunch of options I'm not
sure what the syntax exactly is but you
can query by
URL tabs query oh you can query by URL
okay interesting so that's just like
another scenario where you can maybe get
a Content script injected into your page
oh yeah active true last Focus window
that's how you get access to the
currently active tab
interesting interesting okay I'm getting
a little nerd sniped
here yeah wow okay Sor sorry guys all
right let's get let's get let's get back
to it but I I definitely want to look
into that a little bit more I didn't get
a chance to investigate that before the
show um but that's definitely something
that is very interesting because if it's
dynamically inting injecting those
content scripts um and the logic is a
little bit less defined because I think
in in this scenario like the match
patterns for the the manifest.json file
make it pretty impossible for you to
make a mistake there's not like a lot of
very strict yeah it's it's it's pretty
it's pretty well defined um but if
they're just using something like you
know chrome. tabs query or whatever then
it can be defined user logic and they
could be do using Rex they could be you
know checking the page for a specific
class the existence of a specific class
and then injecting right into that and
so all you need to do is on your techer
control page just build out that div you
know that has a specific class and then
boom now the extension is in your page
and you and you have the ability to mess
with it like we talked about before yeah
and very cool I mean in some extensions
I've seen like very long manifest fights
that have a whole bunch of um pages in
there or or sorry URLs in there so I'm
sure in those cases you can find like
one um really old site and just access
it easily um but yeah that's interesting
in the case you want to look at the
attack surface of having the content
script injected into aalisha page um and
we've covered that we've covered having
the extension injected into an normal
page um and I should mention that the
attx scenarios that we covered in both
of these examples are only the sort of
more general ones um extensions are very
flexible you can have some dumb logic
that they have there um as you mentioned
like getting cookies um just like some
post messages know that get that gets
cookies or something like that yeah it's
possible dude I love it I love it it's
so good so okay so that that makes a lot
of sense for these for the content
descript attacks and we've got two other
sections here attacking extension pages
and attaching attacking service workers
where you want to go next yeah um let's
go with extension pages okay right um so
well hold on let me let me Let me
refresh my memory so extension Pages
those are the things that you define
that are just kind of like static assets
on the on the page or on the extension
right and it and they use the Chrome Das
extension col extension ID which is
going to be the same for everyone right
the extension ID Okay cool so um that we
can craft but there are some limitations
on um how you can interact with those
extension pages I think I think there
might be a bit of a mitigation there I'm
not sure I mean I haven't looked too
deep into it and I'm not sure which
context it's sort of implemented in but
there's some scenario where the um
Chrome extension URL will have like a
unique ID in it that you can't guess but
I haven't actually encountered it um
just know that it's possible somehow I'm
not sure very cool yeah so extension
Pages um you can
um sort of look at them as regular pages
with a very strict CSP that have a bunch
of
um like extra permissions or features um
because they can communicate with the
background script so that can be like
another
sort of way to Pivot you know you can go
either through the content script or
through an extension page oh interesting
yeah so I'm going to give the example oh
first of all the extension Pages by
default they're not going to be
accessible from a regular website and
what I mean by that is you can't open
them with window. open you can't iframe
them you can't do anything with them um
you can't even navigate them like with
location equals like you can't even take
your current page and kill your own
reference and execution and no wow okay
no um so C it's like coupon steroids
there like it's like never get a
reference open this page okay solid
solid I see you Chrome
developers so the if the if that's a
feature that the extension developers
need what they can do is s of of wh list
that specific um HTML file of a specific
page or they can have like a pattern so
what I'm talking about is there's a key
in the Manifest file web accessible
resources um maybe there's also a
dynamic way to define that um I'm not
sure um just not like as a static thing
um but you have the web accessible
resources key and then set has a bunch
of patterns where you can Define which
files included in the zip file of the
extension um are going to be accessible
by regular by regular websites and you
can also Define which website that is so
it can be all websites or it can be like
a specific origin that you trust um and
now that set of websites will be able to
open those sites iframe them if they
don't have any extra restrictions
and stuff like that now what's very
interesting is and now we're getting to
the um bug that was in the metamask um
extension when you have one page that is
web accessible and you sort of iframe it
or open it or something like that and so
you have like page a that is web
accessible and Page B that isn't web
accessible if you can somehow open page
a either in an iframe or in a new tab
and make it redirect to page B then you
can access page
B really so wa you can get a reference
to it yeah you can get the reference to
it you can put it in if
frame W okay so so let's say we have an
extension page that's like redirect HTML
or whatever and it and it takes and that
one is web accessible and we don't even
have to be theoretically we can actually
talk about the metamask bug so because
the details are public and and there's a
BB video about it if you want to learn
more um so the metamask had a specific
page and that was I think like a fishing
warning and it displayed like a whole
bunch of deex and then a link and the
thing that it linked to was like the
value of some URL parameter so that's a
page that they had that was actually web
accessible by any origin oh wow so this
is like perfectly the scenario that we
were okay solid and they had another
page that was like the notification page
it was called but basically it allowed
you to click accept transaction right
the most sensitive clicking you can
never have so the attack scenario was
basically you open that in a attacker
control page you open that um that uh
fishing fishing notification fishing
notification fishing warning page with
like um and you put in the URL parameter
the URL of the very sensitive page that
we definitely don't want to get click
checked now you um make the victim click
on the link that appears inside the um
fishing warning page and now that page
redirects itself to the um to the page
that isn't normally web accessible but
because it just got redirected from a
page that is web accessible you can now
click check it and that's what happens
and they got like 120k that's such a
crazy simple exploit too man oh my gosh
I love how they weaponized the fishing
notification
the the fishing uh warning page like
don't get fished okay cool now click
here click
the click the big red button that
definitely isn't the accept transaction
button thing is I've looked at that
exact same page but just like an
different iteration of it I think they
changed it because of this bug so yeah
it said that I was late to that too sad
man sad that's how that's how the game
works sometime though so um yeah so
there's another trick and that I wasn't
sure if I was going to disclose I can
see you smiling there yes I'm excited
I'm glad you decided to yeah are you
going to disclose it or you're not going
to disos it specifically because I don't
think that's like very exploitable in
the program that I like to act the
extension of going to keep it pretty
vague um so I don't mind sharing it um
but sweet it's I I don't think it's
intended maybe um I hope chrome doesn't
get mad at me um for disclosing this but
um you can get a reference this isn't
like an iframe reference um but just
like a reference to a window um of a
page that isn't normally web accessible
if you can somehow create a scenario
where the victim navigates to that page
right and then in the same tab maybe
after a few navigations navigates to an
attacker control page the reason is
because if you have an attacker control
page and somewhere back in the history
of the same tab you have a
non-accessible page you can do um
history. back and then just go a bunch
of steps until you navigate until you
reach that page and it will let you go
back to it I'm a little bit I'm a little
bit fuzzy on how historyback works so so
if if I run
historyback I don't maintain my my Js
yeah
execution yeah I should clarify that a
little bit and actually it's you can get
a pretty good understanding of it
because you interact with that concept
all the time the little arrows that you
have in the URL bar that just goes back
one history step and forward one history
step so you can imitate that with
JavaScript basically and the attack
scenario that I'm talking about here is
you have a victim somehow um land in the
non-accessible page okay whether they
right click the extensions and went to
options or something like that all copy
pasted the URL here's a here's a
scenario okay so so in our save my jpegs
or whatever extension that we're talking
about it's kind of like Pinterest where
you like you know have a specific uh
image you want to save you click save or
whatever and it goes to maybe it's
displayed all of your saved uh pictures
are displayed in an extension page right
so you click the URL at the top you say
oh let's look at my oh and it links like
to the um profile of the photographer or
something like that exactly and it links
back to the page from which you yoinked
the the the image right so then you're
on that extension page you click the
image it takes you to the page where you
saved it from right right and now it's
in the same history yeah yeah so so then
how do we from there how do we get to
that other page from the from the um
page that you had okay yeah this is
where it gets a little tricky um but I
like those sorts of scenarios with opens
and opener and stuff like that so from
that page that has the non-accessible
page in the history you open an attacker
control page right so or same origin
page like because it's in it's in the
origin of the attacker so you open a
malicious page and now um from that page
um so you have like the um page with the
fancy history with the um non-accessible
page and you open a malicious page right
now um you have to have some way of
making that page that you just opened
the opener of the page with the history
so that it has the ability to navigate
it and stuff okay so in order to do that
you can just have the first window have
some name like a and then from the
second page you go like window. open um
empty string comma a right and that will
just make it um it will both give you a
window reference and it will make it
will make you the opener of the page now
what you do we don't know how many steps
back in the history the um extension
page was right but what you can do I
think I haven't actually tested it but
it sounds like a
um extension pages are served locally
right they're files on your computer
which means the response for them is
going to be very fast as opposed to any
other page so what you can do
interesting yeah what you can do is from
the page that you um the sort of you
have the page with the history and you
have this page where you have persistant
JS execution because it doesn't get
navigated or anything from that page um
you trigger like history. back in the um
in the original page and you measure how
long it takes to navigate and by that I
mean how long it takes for that window
to become cross origin so so can you so
obviously if it was directly in our
scenario from the Save jpegs window you
can go ahead and just go one step go one
one step back right but say there was a
sequence of of steps going going
backwards right right but if it was same
origin you could just do check and see
if you have access to the the the Dom
check and see if you have access to the
Dom oh I don't have access to the Dom
that's the extension page right so if it
was direct attacker control website
attacker control website attacker
control website right right yeah Chrome
extension page right um and and so but
if there was some sort of middleman
there some sort of middleman that's not
your attacker controlled page then can
you still do historyback from that
because it it's your ER or no what what
what I'm trying to do is like from the
page where you have persistent
execution um you go history. back and
measure the delay if it's like over 30
milliseconds or something like that or
50 I don't know how how long um then
you're like oh this isn't the page I
wanted so you navigate it with do
location which you can do because um we
made it the opener
that's why we did that you do do
location and navigate it to um control
page yeah and now you can do window.
back right and specify two steps you can
specify how many steps you want to take
yeah with the offsets and everything
okay yeah and now you skip back right
and then you check that page again see
how long it takes to load if it's not it
you navigate back and you go back two
steps you do that until you get to the
um exension page yeah so even if there's
a middleman even if there's like a a
page that is not same origin with the
attacker origin that is in between the
attacker's origin in the extension page
you can still have a a methodical
approach to stepping back through the
history and getting a reference to that
to that other uh extension page right so
one way yeah one way to um verify if you
landed on the extension pages to see
like the um delay as we mentioned and
the way you measure the delay you sort
of loop trying to access some same
origin attribute like location. hre
sorry property and um as soon as you get
an error you stop the uh counter the
timer so now you know how long it took
to become cross origin after you started
the navigation in this case window. back
um oh hisory do back I haven't tried
this sort of combination of um cross
origin timing with history. I think it
will work though yeah it seem seems It's
a navigation anyway um so you can
identify it via timing or if you know
for example that the extension page will
have seven ey frames you can check
frames. length to see use traditional
traditional crossy leak sort of
techniques to to do that and so now we
have the a window reference either
because it was accessible or because
um we use the weird trick that we lost
you move forward a little bit the
microphone I can't hear you on the
microphone anymore yeah okay there you
go so um we have um a reference to the
non-accessible if you're not determined
um if you're not
determined extension page right now that
you have a reference you can attack it
sort of as a normal page that has a very
strict CSP and so the default CSP
doesn't mention Styles anywhere so if
you can make it somehow inject HTML you
can inject a style and um try to do
stuff with that um yeah somehow um try
to the CSP is going to be strict though
right so so is that a strict CSP that's
just for script for scripts basically
okay so we can still include external
stylesheets in maybe yeah do like
sequential import chaining yeah I wonder
let's let's check into that really quick
to see if we can do sequential import
chaining because then you could um well
I guess even without sequential import
chaining now with some of the research
that came out um uh recently there's
there's ways to do uh to leak the actual
yeah contents of the was that by
um who was that biome I don't recall I'm
I'm drawing a blank on it right now but
man that research was stunning it was
like by um uh the guy from yeah yeah PS
Paul right PS PA great research I liked
his
um like mutation xss stuff too it was
very interesting dude this this CS I
I'll link this I'm just going to drop it
into the doc now so we don't forget but
um wow this this research with just the
scroll bar and just a super in-depth
understanding of key frames and and uh
animations and stuff like that just
absolutely it was insane I still don't
understand it honestly I Tried reading
it like pretty late in the evening on my
phone and I gave up righted the next day
I have somewhat of an understanding of
it but man I consider CSS injection like
one of my things that I really enjoy and
and I I like am pretty decent at and
that just absolutely blew my mind and I
still don't have a full understanding of
it I think for me where the mismatch
occurs is like I I don't understand
these these key frames and Trans in
these animations well enough when
combined with variables in inside of CSS
they got like really deep into um a
bunch of
like yeah just tricks and HS and yeah
yeah but it is amazing to see that it's
it's possible to leak tech text nodes
with CSS without sequential chaining
that's that's revolutionary that is a a
massive dub yeah for sure um so anyways
and the
uh once you have the window reference
the rest is like up to you it's not
there isn't like a very defined way to
go about exploiting it because all of
the like eval eval location all of the
normal things are not going to be viable
here because of the CSP that we
mentioned and so so so just talking
about that CSP value again the default
value for that is script Source self
object Source self so that that is going
to be yeah okay Min and then there's a
minimum uh the minimum uh content
security policy for this is script sore
itself wasm unsafe eval and object
Source self so that's I mean that's
pretty intense but it it doesn't like
you said it doesn't require that you
have some restrictions around CSS so we
can still get read on these Pages via
CSS injection right yeah and um I mean
if that page somehow like if it's an
options page right and it I don't know
gets a post message that changes the
option or something like that you can
get creative there URL parameters though
I'm not sure if you can specify URL
parameters Because unless it's web
accessible though yeah yeah I wonder if
you can change the hash because that
doesn't trigger a refresh right if you
know the path then you should be be able
to do uh but then yeah yeah maybe maybe
I think you should be able to cuz that
doesn't count as a
navigation yeah right that's something
we need we need to test and you're the
opener of the page in the scenario that
we described um
so the attack scenarios for the um uh
extension pages are like one
communication with the uh service
worker right so the same thing that we
had in the um content script two when we
talking about Dome stuff HTML injection
exfiltration of stuff with CSS injection
and um click checking if it's web
accessible or if you can get it a web
accessible page to redirect which I love
the fact that that's possible yeah
that's that's pretty great so so if it's
the thing that's make going to make it
really interesting is if it's web
accessible right there are some weird
scenarios where we can make it web
accessible by this historyback thing
that hopefully Chrome won't patch
because you disclosed it um and and uh
and some other flows right if we can get
a page to redirect to it um but yeah and
then there's also just sort of the
traditional um HTML you know injection
syns in this scenario where like for
example on our on our um save the jpegs
extension right save the jpeg it sounds
like a like a social justice C
save the J they're getting too big
yeah
um they're getting too big that's good U
it's true man it's true 4K um but yeah
if you can if like for example in in the
name of the jpegs or something like that
or the metadata there's some attribute
that contains HTML and the extension
writes that to the Dom of the extension
page then you can trigger HTML injection
there and CSS injection and do something
with that you just can't trigger xss
that's a good example actually that's
something that I forgot to mention not
all attacks are going to require you to
have a window reference right in that
scenario where you can just have like a
sort of stored HTML injection there you
can exploit that without the need for
all the fancy stuff yeah yeah so window
references are only necessary when we're
doing you know post message related
stuff or or um you know trying to affect
the hash potentially and that sort of
thing but otherwise you should be
looking at maybe yeah clicks yeah yeah
or or or you could um yeah clicks but
the but the probably the main attack
scenario is just going to be look at the
business logic that that surrounds that
extension that's that's a theme across
all of the extension hugging
stuff extensions are super flexible and
pretty locked down by
default and so you kind of have to look
at the how they sort of bent the extent
ition and shaped it for their features
and um if you have like I don't know an
account that's connected to the
extension somehow say um we have like
save my j.com and the extension sort of
uses the um cookies of save myex.com to
send like authenticated requests right
yeah um so if you can somehow um get it
to send a malicious request like stuff
like that you know the stuff that isn't
stand out that's interesting that that
is interesting because yeah okay so this
would allow it to send authenticated
requests with even when you're on a a
checker that's that's a very common
pattern I mean all of the a lot of the
big extensions and that are like of some
company um if they want a way to
monetize the extension they're going to
have to connect it to an account and
when they connect it to an account
there's going to be some sort of
authenticated fetch implementation right
um so if you can somehow get into that
um either via I don't know some
communication to some extension page
content script whatever right and
somehow get into that authenticated
fetch yeah yeah that makes sense but
it's sort of an example of more um
custom stuff you know yeah well it it
maps I mean it Maps pretty well also
onto tradition
web hacking right that that in a strict
CSP environment and and maybe a coupe
environment a little bit extra Johan
yeah yeah yeah so so you know what we do
when we see csps is we talk to
Johan yeah no that that makes a lot of
sense all right so we've covered
extension pages and we've covered I'm
gonna I'm gonna take like one second
yeah let's take a break we come back
back yeah yo y'all exciting announcement
real quick we are finally launching the
CTB podcast swag store yeah that's right
the shirts that Joel and I have been
wearing on the Pod for the past couple
months will finally be available for
y'all to purchase at ctbb doow swag we
gave out quite a few of them at Defcon
but if you didn't get your hands on one
or maybe you want some more then uh
definitely check out the swag store also
if you're a critical thinker on Discord
then uh check the Discord Channel
because you'll have a discount code
available for you there or maybe this is
a good opportunity for you to sign up
and become a critical thinker if you're
not already because you'll get a great
discount on the swag um if you do so all
right cool I think that's a wrap uh
anything else I need to tell you about
that I don't think so all right cool
back to the Pod let's
go okay all right so now um hitting the
ground running back to attacking service
workers um the last component of the of
the extension think we'll go about we'll
go through that part a bit quickly
because um we just have a lot of
interesting stuff to talk about after
that sure yeah um but yeah so when we
talk about service workers they're the
sort of Crown Jewel of the extension you
don't have direct access to it and you
don't have direct access to communicate
with it even um so you have to sort of
pivot through either a Content script or
through um extension page an extension
page yeah and um or there's another
possibility which we'll cover in a
second uh oh so many caveats in this
episode yeah um I'm sure there's at
least one um one time where I said we're
going to get to that in a second and we
never got to it sorry sorry audience
sorry about that I'm going to update the
comments or something yeah um so uh
those how that actually looks like is in
the code of the service worker you're
going to have the sort of equivalent of
a message listener for this sort of
communication in
extensions um it's it goes like chrome.
runtime. connect or or sorry do
onconnect oron message okay those are
two separate like listeners and you call
that function um with like a call back
function as a parameter and when that
service worker gets a message it will
call the on message listener now I
mentioned onconnect too what onconnect
does is um It's s of of a functionality
to like from the content script you can
go um Chrome runtime connect and then
that will um give you back like a
message Port that you can communicate
with the okay um yeah with the um
extension and the way that works is you
have like the um the content scripts and
of the message port and I'm not sure
message ports are common knowledge so
I'm just going to cover what that is
yeah yeah yeah very quickly you can
imagine it like you know that um can
with the string I like that analogy I
use it in some show and that's good
that's good I like it so you have like
the can with the string and so you have
like some the way it usually works is
you have some and page you have two
pages communicating and one of the pages
creates that whole channel it's called
which is a collection of two cans with a
string attached now sends a post message
um to the other um to the other page
letting it know that I want to share
like a Channel with you or a port with
you and it sort of transfers the port so
it just throws one of the cans and now
you don't the original page doesn't have
access to the can but the other page can
catch it and now whenever one of the
pages sends a message through their end
of the um of the channel it's going to
come out in the other port and vice
versa
very cool like like a little uh it's
like kind of like those Mario
little you know you come out of a little
pipe you know that sort of thing that to
many analogies yeah I'm not my wife has
banned me from using analogies I need to
stop stop doing it so bad um yeah uh so
in this case with extension specifically
they have sort of a native way to do
that so you don't have to do the whole
exchange and that's called connect so
what happens and I have to prefix that
by saying I haven't actually looked at
it m um like I've only tested it
manually a little but I haven't actually
seen it in action I've read some code
around it though so the way it works is
um you from one of the ends that wants
to initiate a connection either the um
content script or the
umt yeah let's say just for Simplicity
that in this case the content script
wants to um to initiate a connection
with the uh service worker so from the
content script you go chrome. runtime.
connect um and I think you don't have to
pass any um any options but you can pass
a few configuration options to that
function
now um that's going to um trigger a sort
of event in this service worker and
Trigger all of the callbacks for um
chrome. runtime. on connect right and
now all of those are going to get um a
port in like um as one of the arguments
to the function and now they can save
that Port right and the return value of
the chrome. runtime. connect is in the
sort of content script side is going to
be the other end of the channel ah
interesting chrome. time. connect that
automatically creates the two can saves
one of them as the sort of return value
and the other one it um passes to the
arguments of the function of the uh call
back yeah okay so that makes sense and
then the Callback function can interact
with that with that can send messages
both of them can just send messages it's
very it's way easier yeah here's here's
the question then is it like a normal
Port where you can say where the content
um the scpt could pass that Port through
wow I haven't thought of that to the to
the client side through the actual like
uh actual legitimate page environment um
let's see chrome. time.
connect yeah I wonder if that's going to
happen
huh yeah so let's let's let's let's
investigate that for a second hold on
all right all right we're back okay so
run we did investigate that cuz that was
going to be crazy if if that was
possible because that that would lead to
a lot of problems but uh runtime. Port
is the type that is returned from the
runtime. yeah it's not an actual Port
it's not an actual Port so it's not
serializable to pass through as a trans
means that you can send it in a message
yeah and and I think post message in
particular has like a a set of
transferable um anything that can be
encoded using um oh s is using like a
deep clone algorithm I'm not sure what
it's called yeah so array buffer message
Port writable stream audio data image
bit map you're exposing some of my
tricks man hey man you know that's what
you get for coming on the Pod no that's
one that I've been exploiting though all
the different types not going to say
more than that yeah oh snap okay all
right all right I'm said to say that on
the photo hey we if it makes you feel
any better we already covered this in
episodes in the past
so it's already out there um okay yeah
okay so so we get these so all right let
me summarize to this point we when when
it when the content script connects to
the back uh the backend script also
known as the service worker um it it
does this connect and it gets port and
it can interact with that port and the
back end also gets a port where it can
interact so yeah two ways to communicate
one is just sending messages um so just
back and forth messages and not post
messages but sort of the equivalent in
this yeah in this case um or if you want
to make things easier you can have a
connection and then just trigger it like
onconnect um connect/ onconnect sort of
flow and then you get like a channel
where you can just send messages um
quickly right um sure so that's like
what the two um handlers and and um
functions do right now what's
interesting is you have um a separate
set of functions named on message
external and on connect external right
those two are sort of more exposed
versions of the same concept um and they
allow messages and connections from more
sources so by default the way works is
on connect and on message are only going
to be like accessible or you can only
communicate with those um listeners from
either content scripts or um yeah or
uh extension Pages yeah I forgot what we
call them yeah so uh other other than
that you can't like from a malicious
site or something connect to it now
externally connectable or sort of the
sort of I'm getting ahead of myself the
external version of those two by default
allows um other extensions to connect to
it interesting so there's so there's a
an a way for its own content scripts and
its own uh extension pages to
communicate with it by default and then
there's also an external connection
which is a different whole flow and that
is that only for other extensions or is
that also for just like by default by
default it's only for other extensions
okay but you can configure that behavior
so the default um there's like a a key
in the Manifest called externally
connectable where you can specify um the
sort of what other things can um connect
to it the default value is for it to be
accessible by other extensions the like
external versions of the
listeners um but an extension can
specify another value um they can
specify all urls I think and just make
every URL be allowed to connect they can
specify a few Origins um that are
trusted right and then that's like the
only scenario I sort of contradicted
this before but that's the only scenario
where you do actually have direct
communication with the crown jewel right
very interesting okay and then but then
that's interesting because okay so the
only problem is then that we don't have
access to that runtime Port um that
can't be transferred from the content
script to no I mean that's that's a
separate thing right well but but but I
I'm it is a separate thing but here's
the concept though is like if they have
externally connectable right I imagine
that same flow is using that same
runtime. port object if you're using so
that object is instantiable on the
client side it they they have that type
right within the job environment if it's
externally connectable and you somehow
get JS execution in some origin that is
in the externally connectable FL or
property then you can just buy a like on
your own create a port object or send a
message stuff like that just directly
right you don't have to go through a
Content script through anything right do
we have access to like runtime how do
you do that CU there's no runtime object
right that's not window window.
runtime no it's it's chrome. runtime ah
maybe maybe I'm not sure how you
actually do that from on the client side
yeah that's a little weird wait let me
let me check on some side that does have
externally connectable oh so it exposes
the API once you time yeah you do but
not on any okay okay so we're back on
okay so yeah that's very interesting
because there's an API that you didn't
know exist on normal Pages it isn't even
accessible like it's not like a function
that doesn't return anything it just
doesn't exist right but on a page that
is in the external externally
connectable flag I keep calling flag
property whatever on some on some
extension then you have chrome. runtime
the API is exposed and you can go
chrome. runtime. connect CH runtime send
message right m and you need the
extension ID to pass through and then
connect to that and then so that's why
when I just popped open my Dev console
there because I don't have any
extensions that have externally a
connectable set for for my specific
origin that I was on that's why I didn't
see the chrome. run time but if I was on
an origin that did have that then I
would have the uh that Chrome API yeah
and as you mentioned when it's called
from an from a web from a web page you
need to specify a specific extension ID
otherwise it doesn't know which
extension you're trying to connect to
that makes sense look at that yeah I do
I went to a page that I that I have it
on and it's there that's really
interesting so
there's there are two ways to get um to
the externally or external listeners
right the listeners that have externally
in the end one um you go to an
externally
connectable um and that's that's
assuming that they have even an
externally connectable um option in
their manifest you go to an externally
connectable page and exploit it xss
something like that two is um if you if
the if they either don't have that um
config in there or they have a config
that allows for um extensions to connect
um then if the victim installs a
malicious browser extension which is a
bit of a worse attack scenario yeah um
because in that case I mean
uh share you can make them install a
browser extension that has like very
little Privileges and then escalate to a
browser extension that has a lot of
privileges but I don't think users
actually check what level of privilege
the extension actually asks for but um I
think that's still a valid attack
scenario well the the other thing about
that is the same sort of thing you run
across with mobile apps is that these
it's very easy to gain access to some
will just ask them yeah or do like a
sply chain attack or um you can buy
chroming this is the thing that you know
cuz there's two sides of Justin right
there's there's the there's the um the
hacker Justin but there's also the
business Justin and the business Justin
loves uh investigating you know all
sorts of weird businesses and stuff like
that and one of the ones I was just
absolutely Blown Away by is Chrome
extensions are freaking cheap dude you
can buy Chrome extensions like for like
one cent per per install like less than
one cent per install and so you can I
mean how much is that for a million
installs like 10K yeah it's I mean it it
gets cheap man cheap cheap So like um it
it can be it can be very easy to get a
hook into a ton of users browsers via a
Chrome extension so if you have to argue
for that yeah go for yeah they're
they're cheap dude but there's not a
really great way to monetize them either
that's the problem is like from the
business but this isn't a business
podcast this is a he podcast so I won't
spend too much time on that um either
way this is really cool dude and I
didn't expect for that object to not
even exist in the the JS execution
environment if if it if it didn't if
there wasn't a a Chrome extension that
exposed that um
also that's a caveat that I mean I'm
happy I am I just remember to
mention um you can have on connectors on
connectors external and on message
external listeners not only on service
workers but also on extension Pages oh
interesting okay so extension Pages can
actually listen for external connections
and messages so from like a malicious
extension you can go and connect to the
um page oh I wonder you wouldn't even
need to be in the same you wouldn't need
a window reference or tab group no no
you can just connect to it oh that's
that's interesting okay so that's
definitely something that we need to be
on top of when we're reading the the
Chrome extension code is is checking
whether the connected on message okay
I'm not sure how you would even like
CVSs that CVSs ify it and the
requirement for
um another Chrome extension installed
another Chrome extension installed um
yeah I mean it's definitely going to be
attack complexity High I think uh yeah I
think that would be maybe develop an
extension have a bunch of people install
it and then be like it's not a
requirement I that you know jokes on you
triager it's browser right now yeah yeah
a month after this episode drops you
hear about the crazy new ctbb extension
that just just developed install it from
the
oven um Okay cool so that's a lot of
things to look at um one of the things
that I wanted to swing back around to
was um you know we covered a lot about
the structure we covered a lot about the
attack model surrounding these um these
extensions uh how do we get access to
the source code that we are talking
about reviewing right right also one
little thing before we um continue from
the structure I didn't mention one and
it was intentional because I didn't want
to get it to to for it to beit too
confusing but um extensions can have a
another component
because three or four wasn't enough they
can have like a native component so if
you have like um and that's what um
space
raccoon um that's what he mentioned and
goes deep into in his um blog exploiting
that specific one but I think like
having an extension is already nich
enough having an extension that has a
bug Bounty program so if you had another
requirement on top of that that's like
way too Niche yeah and but I think he
was able to monetize it at least a
little bit yeah yeah I mean he found a
lot of crazy bugs because he was there's
a a big query data set that parses these
manifest files um it's it's sort of an
intersection of just
like it's sort of an intersection of
just like JS hacking which is pretty
like rare end extension knowledge and
and Native knowledge so you get like
very very specific and you won't have a
lot of competition it is it is something
you see with with um with password
managers though
and I think password managers are more
likely to have a bug Bounty program
because of the sensitive nature of the
content is there's often a a native
component and a extension component
because of those that integration so
definitely some good attack scenarios
there a lot of the password managers
don't pay enough which makes me very
worried as one that's very sad yeah yeah
as a person that uses a like stores
basically his old Digital Life in a pule
same I wish they paid higher same dude
am is yeah um all right so how do we get
our hands on this code okay so this code
most of the time you're going to have
just minified code and that's just the
reality of the situation um you have to
like being able to read a minifi code is
a skill that if you don't already have
it's going to be valuable to get it
anyways and it just takes a lot of
practice there isn't a shortcut to that
um but in some cases the extension is
going to be open source or something and
you will be able to get it um but in the
normal case um the extension the sort of
file that um Chrome downloads from the
web store and installs is is called like
a CRX file and you can unzip it with the
um Regular unzip utility it's sort of
like an APK um it's just like a regular
zip file with a whole bunch of other
meta data on top of it and in the
beginning of the actual file um so one
way to down load a Chrome extension is
to go is to download the uh CRX file you
can either go to one of the websites
that have the CRX files but I wouldn't
go through a third party you can install
it uh you can download the CRX file
straight from the um web store if you
can uh if you interact with the um API
that the web store uses um there's one
like um URL that I wrote in the doc you
can maybe put it in the description or
something yeah but um there's one URL
where you can just put the extension ID
and you can W get it and um it will just
download uh the extension nice it'll
just drop the whole the whole um yeah
and uh CRX file okay got you there isn't
a way to download previous versions so
I'd recommend like downloading it once
in a while and diffing it or something
like that so you can see the
changes um but another thing that you
can do which is I think easier you can
just install the extension normally on
your browser if you don't want to um
clutter up your um browser you can open
like a separate uh browser profile it's
called and um what you can do is just
install it and then CH will actually put
the source code of it in a specific
folder yeah that's what I normally do
the app data folder for for Windows um
in Windows it's app data
um
local goog Chrome but you can just find
yeah you can find the path of it if you
go to um about colum version um it will
show you the path of it for your um for
the profile that you're currently using
because for different profiles that have
different extensions installed you will
have different folders so you will see
the profile path and you just go to that
path and then to the extension folder
extensions folder in there
and then you you'll have to go to the
extension with the ID the way you um
figure out what the extension ID is is
you go to manage extensions enable
developer mode and it will just show it
there sure yeah solid so there's a
couple ways to get get access to the
source code for that and then you're off
to the races finding these uhy the code
and then you you have it and and so what
is live debugging what does dynamic
debugging look like for these yeah so um
debugging them is very important because
when you deal with minified source code
it makes your life way easier to
actually debug stuff um so there's a bit
of setup that you have to do with Dev
tools and I have the actual steps
mentioned here let me find it real quick
um so you have to go to the dev tool
settings and that's sort of um to make
debugging available for Content scripts
um so you go to the um Dev to settings
and then like to delet gear at the top
right corner when you open Dev tools and
then um you go to preferences and under
sources you have to enable search in
Anonymous and content scripts and that
will enable the search to match um code
that's in content scripts like the
global search control shift F and you
also have to remove content scripts from
the ignore list so you go to the ignore
list sort of section um on the left left
and you disable content scripts injected
by extensions okay I'm I'm now I
actually don't have uh I don't have this
set up uh in mind so I need to collect
preferences search okay yeah preferences
and in the ignore list you have to
disable content scripts and you can
disable in the preferences or enable
yeah it's the first preference on
sources yeah m
oh this one you have to disable yeah we
want that cont scripts injector by
extensions okay got Co now you you're
good to debug ex um content scripts the
way you actually do that you can go to
sources and in the sources you have a
few sections where it normally says page
you can go and you can pick content
scripts and it will show you all the
content scripts and their sources you
can put like break points in there and
if you want to evaluate code in the sort
of context of the uh content script um
you go to the sort of where you pick the
context which can be like top or some if
frame or something like that and simply
pick like the um extension that you want
to thebug nice okay that that makes it
easier be inside the isolated world in
the isolated World You' infiltrated it
uh no that's that's great um and
actually this this tip just really
helped me a lot because uh definitely I
want to have this turned on for when I'm
working with extensions but dude every
single time I freaking open the dev
console for some reason my my and and I
go to sources it defaults to content
scripts oh yeah me too it's so I hate it
dude because then I've got to go to page
and it just adds like another couple
clicks when I just really should have
just opened it up to the thing that I
want so actually I'm going to go into my
preferences and and turn off Dev tools
yeah ironically somebody at Google needs
to debug Dev tools yeah because um
that's it's a bit buggy like sometimes
when I try to see like the HTML code of
the page when they go to sources it
shows like a blank editor and I have to
refresh for it to actually show me the
code it's a bit annoying it's buggy man
it's buggy it's for devs though so you
know we we we take what we can get so
now that you can debug content scripts
you can do that see all of the um break
points like um variables Etc um when if
you want to debug the service worker
part um you can go to when the service
worker is sort of active and because
they sort of get loaded and unloaded
when needed um you can go to about colon
inspect and and then you have a section
for service worker service workers uh in
the left there's section for extensions
too um which inspects like a separate
part but just go to service workers okay
service workers okay yeah and then you
have a whole bunch of stuff um I hope
you didn't leak anything important yeah
I I might I might have the uh the the
video editor gu blur those out so not
everybody I mean it's only extension IDs
but yeah yeah yeah okay cool well that
makes sense so we can we can um go in
there and click inspect and then we can
in in uh debug those service workers and
that's those are all the components
we've got service workers we got the
content scripts we've got the uh we've
got the extension pages and I imagine
the extension Pages they're just sort of
like normal Dev tools debugging um for
those so I'm going to mention that as
much as we did talk about the structure
and stuff there are a whole bunch of
Concepts that we skipped because they
aren't as relevant um like I think
they're called background Pages or oh
offscreen Pages that's what they're
called whole bunch of stuff you can yeah
you can look at that in the uh Chrome so
Chrome docks they explain stuff pretty
well and if you want to now are we gonna
move on from extensions yeah dude I
think that puts a wrap on the extensions
and I'll tell you what Monon this one
this one's we we've done a lot of stuff
on this one so actually I think we'll
cut it here for today and then we'll
actually go and and talk about this this
cookie yeah we're ending every episode
on a cliffhanger dude we we are man but
but actually what what we'll do
listeners is um we'll actually just cut
it here for my editor's sake so I don't
overwork them too much and uh we'll go
record the next episode right away so we
don't lose any momentum here and we'll
have that up the week after after that
okay um so maton dude thanks for the uh
for the master class on on uh like
browser extension hacking dude the the
structure the attack vectors this is
exactly what we need to know to start
poking at these so um great work man it
was great being here I always enjoy it
as always yeah thanks for having me all
right let's go get that cookie stuff
let's go and that's a wrap on this
episode of critical thinking thanks so
much for listening and if you want more
critical thinking content head over to
ctbb show/ Discord join the Discord
there's lots of great conversations and
chats going on over there and if you
want to support the show there's the
Discord subscriber tiers which give you
access to master classes amas hack along
alongs exclusive scripts and an
exclusive chat Channel with us we'll see
you there
[Music]